

Gustavo Rayos













575-520-5199

gustavorayos @outlook.com San Francisco Bay Area gustavorayos.com

@gustavorayos

@gustavorayos

Summary

Linux Systems Administrator/Engineer since 2015. Currently holds an <u>active DoD Secret Security Clearance</u> and is <u>CompTIA Security+ Certified</u>. Experienced in Information Systems Engineering, Linux/Windows Administration, and Cyber Security. Performs systems configuration, deployment automation, OS patching, vulnerability management, and data management. Received <u>Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science</u> from New Mexico State University in 2015.

Skills

LANGUAGES

TECHNOLOGIES

• Bash

Python

• PowerShell

• DOS / Windows

JavaScript

• CSS

• HTML

- RHEL
- Ubuntu
- Fedora
- VMWare
- Hyper-V
- Ansible
- SCAP / STIGViewer

- Active Directory
- Group Policy
- WDS & MDT
- SCCM
- Tenable
- NFS / Samba
- MacOS

Experience

LINUX SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR/ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

Navy Fleet Weather Center - Federated IT | San Diego, CA | May 2023 - Current

- Updated existing infrastructure from RHEL 7.5 to RHEL 8.10.
- Configured unclassified and classified DISA repositories on RHEL 8.10 servers for monthly patching cycles.
- Worked closely with Cyber Security (Information System Security Officers (ISSOs)) to remediate vulnerabilities reported by Nessus/ACAS.
- Deployed RHEL IDM Management server with custom 3rd party certificates.
- Performed vulnerability scans using SCAP Tool, STIGViewer, STIGs, and Tenable.
- Automated quarterly SCAP scans and forwarded SCAP results to central repository.
- Configured NFS shares on Linux systems.
- Patched VMware ESXi hypervisors and VCSA appliances.
- Patched Splunk Enterprise servers.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

SENIOR INFORMATION SYSTEMS SECURITY ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE) Lockheed Martin Space | Sunnyvale, CA | November 2020 – March 2023

- Developed Kickstart scripts to automate Linux workstation and server deployments.
- Designed and developed Powershell scripts to automate Windows system deployments.
- Designed and developed scripts to harden/configure systems to meet compliance standards of Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA).
- Performed vulnerability scans using SCAP Tool, STIGViewer, STIGs, and Tenable.
- Automated log collection, log scanning, SCAP scanning and STIG configuration.
- Performed remediation, developed POAMs, and supported 3rd party and internal security audits.

- Worked with networking team to troubleshoot network issues between client and server.
- Configured NFS and Samba shares on Linux systems.
- Configured DNS and DHCP services on Linux and Windows servers and workstations.
- Deployed Tang services to automate the access of LUKs encrypted drives on the network.
- Designed VMware test environment to test software and deployments before production.
- Deployed and administered Ansible Configuration Management server on multiple networks.
- Deployed authentication NIS servers and SSSD on multiple information systems.
- Configured Real Time Systems (RedHawk) for THAAD Missile System.
- Analyzed and assessed server performance, storage capacity and planning for future needs.
- Deployed NetApp storage device and configured OnTap services.
- Performed general Linux file management and access management using POSIX.
- Physically installed server and associated hardware in data center and server room.
- Successfully installed/configured software; Gitlab, Docker, Doors, Matlab, etc.
- Created/edited Standard Operating Instructions (SOI) documentation.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

SYSTEMS ENGINEER (DOD SECRET SECURITY CLEARANCE)

Raytheon Missile Systems | Tucson, AZ | March 2019 - October 2020

- Developed software packages to automate standard OS configuration on test equipment.
- Deployed a Windows Deployment Server (WDS) and Microsoft Deployment Toolkit (MDT) server and was responsible for task sequence configuration and client system deployment.
- Configured Windows and RHEL operating system to STIG standards.
- Worked closely with Cyber Security configuring hardware and software.
- Attended Sigma Six discussions providing useful feedback as a member of a project team.
- Participated in system design, security solutions, system imaging, data recovery, hardware diagnostics, and unique problem solutions in multiple heterogeneous network environments.
- Assisted with managing user accounts, network access, generation and maintenance of web-page content, infrastructure, database support, and system backups.
- DoD Secret Security Clearance.

SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR (DOE Q SECURITY CLEARANCE)

CNS Pantex | Amarillo, TX | December 2015 - March 2019

- Attended weekly Vulnerability Assessment Management meetings with Cyber Security and discussing vulnerabilities and remediation plans on systems.
- Calculated Site Performance Review (SPR) monthly metrics, and reviewed system compliance on the Pantex network. Average monthly system compliance on the Pantex network was 99% compliant.
- Reviewed and approved non-standard security exceptions for individual users and systems.
- Developed security protocols and procedures using various tools including PowerShell scripts, SCCM, Group Policy, Active Directory, Tenable, Splunk, Citrix, and more.
- Created and configured standalone system media for government issued laptops.
- Acted as a direct contact for any VPN related issues.
- DoE Q Top Secret Security Clearance

Education

BACHELORS DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

New Mexico State University | Las Cruces, NM | August 2010 - December 2015

Followed my passion for computers and programming and excelled in Java and C programming courses, network security and architecture, and completed research on HPC systems and software. Minored in Software Development and Algorithms Theory. Graduated with a 3.5 GPA.